A Guide to the Joseph Francis Fletcher Papers (1931-1991)
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
Joseph Francis Fletcher Papers, 1931-1991
Historical Collections, Claude Moore Health Sciences Library, University of Virginia
MS-27
16.5 linear feet; 33 5"x10.5"x15.5" manuscript boxes and 2 13"x11"x16.5" boxes
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Mary Faith Marshall, Ph.D., donated the papers to the library in 2001.
Biographical/Historical Information
Joseph Francis Fletcher (1905-1991), a theologian and medical ethicist, social activist and scholar, was a life-long advocate for humane solutions to the problems of modern life. Fletcher spent the majority of his professional career at Cambridge, Massachusetts' Episcopal Theological School, where he held the Robert Treat Paine chair of Social Ethics from 1944 to 1970. Subsequently, he joined the University of Virginia Medical School faculty as the University's first professor of medical ethics (1970-1983). With medical school dean Thomas Harrison Hunter, Fletcher established the Program in Biology and Society and the Medical Center Hour lecture series. Both were early expressions of the critical importance of the humanities to the practice of medicine, and both innovations later bore fruit in the University's Center for Biomedical Ethics, founded in 1988, and the Center for Humanism in Medicine in 1990. The Medical Center Hour continues to bring challenging weekly discussions to the University and on-line communities.
Fletcher began childhood in New Jersey, but as a nine-year-old boy moved with his sister and mother to his maternal family's home in West Virginia. There he remained for a decade, completing high school in three years instead of the usual four, and at age 16 started three years of coursework at the state university at Morgantown. Initially, West Virginia University denied him a diploma because of his radical thinking, though ultimately the faculty relented and granted Fletcher an A.B. degree five years later, in 1929. Always an independent-minded young man, Fletcher had worked one high-school summer for the Consolidation Coal Company, management side, and the next as a trapper boy in the shafts of a small mining operation; from these experiences he developed a lasting sympathy for mine workers and a deep commitment to the struggle to unionize. This era of the late teens and early twenties was a period of great radicalism -- analogous, Fletcher later stated, to the period of social transformations of the 1960s -- and young Joseph read voraciously much of the literature critical of unregulated capitalism, in addition to working on the education staff of the United Mine Workers' local, and volunteering with the Sacco-Vanzetti Defense Committee -- the bellwether legal case pitting liberal critique against conservative patriotism.
During this period of intellectual development and activism, Fletcher became convinced that "Christianity... had a tremendous imperative for social justice," and that the social change he sought could be achieved through the church. ("Memoir," p.7). In consequence, the nineteen-year-old enrolled at Berkeley Divinity School, an Episcopal seminary then located in Middletown, Connecticut. After completing his coursework, Fletcher undertook a multi-year research project for the National Council of the Episcopal Church, which led to the publication of his first book, The Church and Industry (1930), co-authored with Spencer Miller. Fletcher received his Masters of Divinity in 1929, along with a prestigious fellowship for further study: he took courses in economic history at Yale, then traveled abroad to study at the London School of Economics with Richard H. Tawney, a scholar likewise intrigued by the church's potential for social reform.
Fletcher and his wife, Forrest Hatfield -- whom he had met at West Virginia University and married before receiving his divinity degree -- returned to the States from England in 1932. They moved to Raleigh, North Carolina, where Fletcher taught at Saint Mary's Junior College, and proceeded to enrage the local bishop by involving himself with the Piedmont Organizing Council of the United Textile Workers' Union. At the close of his third academic year there, Fletcher resigned and took a double appointment as Dean of Saint Paul's Cathedral in Cincinnati, Ohio and first Dean of a new Graduate School of Applied Religion. Fletcher remained in Cincinnati nine years, from 1936 to 1944, directing this certificate program for seminarians and junior clergy. The curriculum centered on the practical aspects of community services organization and the design of outreach programs. While in Cincinnati, Fletcher also taught social ethics at Hebrew Union College, and courses in labor history for the University of Cincinnati, the local Cincinnati unions, and, in Mississippi, for the Southern Tenant Farmers' Union organizing project, where he was twice subjected to beatings, not only for the labor work itself but also because of the union's interracial staff and membership. The virulent anti-communists of this and later eras viewed Fletcher with profound mistrust -- particularly when he advocated substantive meetings of both sides -- though he pithily summed up his life-long position by stating, "[the] war against fascism is a war against dictatorship, whether of the left or right... of the proletariat or the racists." ("Memoir," p. 19).
The stimulating intellectual atmosphere of Cambridge, Massachusetts drew Fletcher to the Episcopal Theological School (ETS) as World War II was ending. Here his scholarship of ethics matured, as represented in numerous publications -- seven more books and well over a hundred papers. "My heart was in the front line," Fletcher stated, but academic life became his dominant zone of activity. ("Memoir," p. 11). Yet for all the theoretical contemplation, Fletcher remained quintessentially a pragmatist, and his method of pedagogy using case studies constantly recalled the discussion to its most practical elements. This concern with the particular over the universal revolutionized ethical studies. Fletcher argued that the simple charge to love one's neighbor as one's self -- the Christian ethic of love -- supplanted orthodoxy and conventional moral values, a notion as new and radical as it was original to Christian thought. "My main principle," Fletcher wrote, was "that concern for human beings should come before moral rules, and that particular cases and situations are more determinant of what we ought to do than 'universal' norms are." ("Memoir," p. 24). This attitude underlies all of his writing, but above all exemplifies his two most influential books: Morals and Medicine (1954), and Situation Ethics (1966).
Today scholars consider Morals and Medicine the inaugural work of bioethics. Fletcher believed it to be the first contemporary treatment of medical ethical issues developed outside the boundaries of the decalogue, that is, without reliance on the biblical ten commandments so crucial to orthodox theology. Framed in terms of human rights, Morals and Medicine addresses the patient's right to be informed truthfully of medical diagnoses, to control conception -- including use of artificial insemination or sterilization -- and to employ euthanasia. Fletcher's arguments overturned the traditional paternalistic approach of medical practice and challenged physicians and patients to confront moral questions directly, ultimately rejecting the artificial isolation of science from ethics.
With Situation Ethics, Fletcher refined his thesis still further, and crafted an approach to ethical problems of all types. The book was an instant best-seller "about ideas whose time had come," he modestly stated.("Recollections," number 126). No less controversial for all its popularity, Situation Ethics also earned rebukes from the doctrinaire and frightened. Fletcher engaged their objections in The Situation Ethics Debate(1968) and in countless lectures and conversations, but the irony was not lost on him that much opposition came from religious communities. Fletcher's consequentialist resolve never wavered, and he began to find in humanism a more apposite and logical framework than Christian faith and theology. Shortly before his retirement from ETS, Fletcher left the church, "to keep faith with myself, without anger and with lots of thanks to [the church] for many things." ("Memoir," p. 27).
Thus Fletcher began another absorbing career, as first professor of medical ethics at the University of Virginia Medical School. "As I used to tell people, nobody could believe how much I learned after I was sixty-five years old," he stated of his characteristic energy. ("Memoir," p. 28) Besides developing new courses, pursuing an active traveling lecture schedule, publishing numerous papers, and holding additional visiting professorships at the University of Texas and at Australia's Monash University, Fletcher wrote two new books, The Ethics of Genetic Control (1974) and Humanhood: Essays in Biomedical Ethics (1979), bringing the total to ten. The Hastings Center recognized his innovative work in biomedical ethics with the Beecher Award in 1981, and the national medical honor society, Alpha Omega Alpha elected him in 1982 an honorary fellow, the only scholar from the humanities to be so recognized in the organization's history. Fletcher retired from the University of Virginia in 1983, though the University's Board of Visitors annually extended to him the honorary title "visiting scholar" until his death in 1991.
References
"Memoir of an Ex-Radical," Joseph Francis Fletcher Papers (20: 29).
"Recollections," Joseph Francis Fletcher Papers (20: 31).
Scope and Content Information
The Joseph Francis Fletcher Papers comprise two groups of materials: correspondence and subject files. The correspondence files consist almost entirely of professional letters written to Dr. Fletcher throughout his career as a theologian and ethicist, including numerous letters from members of the general public reacting to his most famous and controversial book, Situation Ethics (1966). The subject materials are presented in various categories, often assembled by Dr. Fletcher himself. These include correspondence and related items on the Chinese Revolution, the Episcopal Church magazine "The Churchman," the Bishop Paddock Fund, and the World Peace Movement. Other materials include notes and case studies related to ethical issues presented in his courses and seminars, numerous texts of Fletcher's lectures and sermons, manuscript drafts, and reprints of articles by Fletcher and others. In addition, the subject collections include miscellaneous newspaper clippings, reviews of Fletcher's publications, programs and brochures from his speaking engagements, and scrapbooks containing examples of all types of items assembled by Fletcher early in his career. Rounding out the collection are a series of interview transcripts made near the end of his life, and a folder containing autobiographical essays.
Arrangement
The collection comprises 35 boxes. Boxes 001 to 015 contain correspondence, arranged chronologically, one letter to a folder. Boxes 016 to 031 contain related materials, ordered by an alphabetical sequence of subject headings, as follows: Chinese Revolution, Churchman, Ethical Issues, Financial, Humor, Interview Transcripts, Lectures, Manuscripts, Memoirs, Miscellaneous Clippings, Notes, Paddock Fund, Programs and Brochures, Reprints-Fletcher, Reprints-Miscellaneous, Reviews, Sermons, and World Peace Movement. Within each of these 18 subject headings, items are organized chronologically wherever possible. Boxes 032 and 033 contain oversize materials: scrapbooks assembled by Fletcher and a small collection of photographs, placques, and posters. Boxes 034 and 035 contain additional materials: manuscripts, miscellaneous documents, and student papers.
Contents List
- Forrest [Fletcher] to Joe [Joseph Fletcher], 1931 May 8 (Box-folder 001:001)
- Frank Woods to Sir, 1931 October 11 (Box-folder 001:002)
- [ ] to Joseph Fletcher, 1933 December 8 (Box-folder 001:003)
- David T. Eaton to Joe [Joseph Fletcher], 1934 March 6 (Box-folder 001:004)
- Cameron P. Hall to Joseph Fletcher, 1939, March 14 (Box-folder 001:005)
- E. M. W. Castle to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure, 1930s (Box-folder 001:006)
- Sh. Pollard to Joseph Fletcher, 1943 October 1 (Box-folder 001:007)
- Charlie to Joseph Fletcher, 1944 May 11 (Box-folder 001:008)
- James L. Tryon to Joseph Fletcher, 1945 April 22 (Box-folder 001:009)
- C. L. T. Jr. to [ ] Shepherd, Joseph Fletcher, [ ] Wold, [ ] Buck, [1946] (Box-folder 001:010)
- Milton L. Osgood to Joseph Fletcher, 1948 February 19 (Box-folder 001:011)
- T. S. Eliot to Joseph Fletcher, 1948 March 2 (Box-folder 001:012)
- Irene P. Monfort to Joseph Fletcher, 1948 August 11 (Box-folder 001:013)
- Zach Chafee, Jr. to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 February 16 (Box-folder 001:014)
- Latelle M. La Follette, Jr. to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 May 24 (Box-folder 001:015)
- J. Josephine Tucher to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 May 27 (Box-folder 001:016)
- Henry W. Hobson to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 July 7 (Box-folder 001:017)
- Henry W. Hobson to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 August 29 (Box-folder 001:018)
- Morison R. Waite to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 August 31 (Box-folder 001:019)
- Henry W. Hobson to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 September 7 (Box-folder 001:020)
- Henry W. Hobson to Joseph Fletcher, with attachement1949 September 22 (Box-folder 001:021)
- Henry W. Hobson to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 September 24 (Box-folder 001:022)
- Correspondence and notes concerning the Episcopal Church Foundation, 1949 November 9, December 1, N.D., 10 items (Box-folder 001:023)
- F. M. Cowles to Joseph Fletcher, 1949 December 11 (Box-folder 001:024)
- Brigid to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 January 19 (Box-folder 001:025)
- James M. Schuck to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 February 9 (Box-folder 001:026)
- Paul and Eileen Lin to Friends, with attached note, 1950 March 11 (Box-folder 001:027)
- Jessie M. G. Street to [ ], [1950] May 11 (Box-folder 001:028)
- Louise MacInnes to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 May 22 (Box-folder 001:029)
- Kurt Merz to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 June 23 (Box-folder 001:030)
- Rae Everitt to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure 1950 July 12 (Box-folder 001:031)
- Ralph de Boissiere to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 July 13 (Box-folder 001:032)
- Choming T. Chen to Joseph Fletcher and Forrest Fletcher, 1950 August 9 (Box-folder 001:033)
- Lloyd G. Churchward to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 August 31 (Box-folder 001:034)
- Hershell Johnson to [ ] Niemoller, 1950 August 10 (Box-folder 001:035)
- Frantisek Vrba to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 September 1 (Box-folder 001:036)
- Herlett Johnson to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 September 12 (Box-folder 001:037)
- Nell Simpson to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 September 20 (Box-folder 001:038)
- Jean Laffitte to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 September 22 (Box-folder 001:039)
- Ilya Ehrenburg to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 September 24 (Box-folder 001:040)
- G. Fenoaltea and Jean Lafitte to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 September 26 (Box-folder 001:041)
- Farnham E. Maynard to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 October 25 (Box-folder 001:042)
- Lloyd G. Churchward to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 October 29 (Box-folder 001:043)
- Gilbert Cope to [Joseph Fletcher], 1950 October (Box-folder 001:044)
- Invitation to Reception, USSR October Revolution Anniversary, 1950 [October] (Box-folder 001:045)
- [Nadia] L. Hromadka to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 November 28 (Box-folder 001:046)
- Violette Garmaise-Roy to Joseph Fletcher, 1950 December 29 (Box-folder 001:047)
- Majorie, Cyril, and John Fowles to [Joseph Fletcher], 1950 [December] (Box-folder 001:048)
- Youri I. Gouk to Joseph Fletcher, [1950] (Box-folder 001:049)
- Activities Reports for Joseph Fletcher to the Trustees of the Episcopal Theological School, 1950-1959, 10 Items (Box-folder 001:050)
- Charles W. Chandler to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 January 25 (Box-folder 001:051)
- Kurt Herz to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 February 12 (Box-folder 001:052)
- Nadia l. Hromadka to Joseph Fletcher, with photographs, 1951 February 15 (Box-folder 001:053)
- V. Makarov to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 March 27 (Box-folder 001:054)
- K. H. Ting to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 May 30 (Box-folder 001:055)
- K. H. Ting to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 June 1 (Box-folder 001:056)
- Gordon Boyce to Joseph Fletcher, 1951 June 11 (Box-folder 001:057)
- Rochard A. Strong to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure, 1952 January 29 (Box-folder 001:058)
- Richard A. Strong to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 January 29 (Box-folder 001:058)
- George Guest to Forrest and Joseph Fletcher, 1952 February 2 (Box-folder 001:059)
- Larry to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 February 11 (Box-folder 001:060)
- J. Albert Dalton to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 February 23 (Box-folder 001:061)
- Will to Forrest and Joseph Fletcher, 1952 February 23 (Box-folder 001:062)
- Iago Galdston to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 February 29 (Box-folder 001:063)
- Ralph de Boissiere to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 March 29 (Box-folder 001:064)
- George Peabody to Forrest and Joseph Fletcher, 1952 April 5 (Box-folder 001:065)
- Dale L. Van Meter to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 April 22 (Box-folder 001:066)
- Frank Huntley to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 May 27 (Box-folder 001:067)
- Charles E. Taylor to Joseph Fletcher, with photograph, 1952 June 1 (Box-folder 001:068)
- William Bradley to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 June 16 (Box-folder 001:069)
- A. R. PZP to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 July 3 (Box-folder 001:070)
- Charlie to Colleagues [at the Episcopal Theological School], 1952 July 11 (Box-folder 001:071)
- Dudley Scott Stan[ ] to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 July 17 (Box-folder 001:072)
- Wedding invitation for Marion Evelyn Stewart and George Lewis Blackman, 1952 July 29 (Box-folder 001:073)
- Paul Coste to Joseph Fletcher, with 2 enclosures, 1952 August 9 (Box-folder 001:074)
- Russell Henry Stafford to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 September 16 (Box-folder 001:075)
- April L. Hudson to Joseph and Forrest Fletcher, 1952 (Box-folder 001:076)
- Sam M. Shoemaker to Joseph Fletcher, 1952 December 16 (Box-folder 001:077)
- Henry W. Hobson to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 January 22 (Box-folder 001:078)
- Andre de San Phalle to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 February 11 (Box-folder 001:079)
- Art Miller to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 March 1 (Box-folder 001:080)
- [Arthur Lichtenberger] to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 March 30 (Box-folder 001:081)
- A. Bereecoby[?] to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 April 7 (Box-folder 001:082)
- [William B. Spofford] to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 May 16 (Box-folder 001:083)
- Ned Cole, Jr. to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 May 18 (Box-folder 001:084)
- Willard L. Sperry to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 May 18 (Box-folder 001:085)
- Ted S to Joseph Fletcher, [1953] May 18 (Box-folder 001:086)
- William B. Spofford to L. M. Follette, 1953 May 21 (Box-folder 001:087)
- Cyril E. Hudson to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 July 6 (Box-folder 001:088)
- William E. Jenner to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 July 22 (Box-folder 001:089)
- Jocko to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 July 26 (Box-folder 001:090)
- Richard L. Hurlbut to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure, 1953 August 18 (Box-folder 001:091)
- Len to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 September 28 (Box-folder 001:092)
- Corliss Lamont to Joseph Fletcher, [1953 September] (Box-folder 001:093)
- Gerald H. Anderson to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 October 6 (Box-folder 001:094)
- H. Baker to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 October 6 (Box-folder 001:095)
- R. B. Y. Scott to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 November 5 (Box-folder 001:096)
- Barbara Beye Lorie to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 November 28 (Box-folder 001:097)
- Izette de Forest to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 December 1 (Box-folder 001:098)
- William Stringfellow to Joseph Fletcher, 1953 December 14 (Box-folder 001:099)
- John A. Kingsbury to Joseph Fletcher, [1953 December] (Box-folder 001:100)
- Forrest Hatfield Fletcher to G. Clare Backhurst, 1954 January 8 (Box-folder 001:101)
- Spencer Miller, Jr. to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 January 29 (Box-folder 001:102)
- [Hette de Forest] to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 January 31 (Box-folder 001:103)
- Eugene V. N. Goetchius to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 February 7 (Box-folder 001:104)
- Harry F. Ward to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 February 7 (Box-folder 001:105)
- Francis Touchet to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 February 11 (Box-folder 001:106)
- Gordon C. Graham to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 February 16 (Box-folder 001:107)
- Charlie L. Taylor to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 March 14 (Box-folder 001:108)
- John S. Sexton to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 March 18 (Box-folder 001:109)
- Theodore Bayer to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 March 25 (Box-folder 001:110)
- B. Loring Young to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 March 25 (Box-folder 001:111)
- Florence Fisher to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 April 5 (Box-folder 001:112)
- Howard to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 April 20 (Box-folder 001:113)
- [Vida D. Scudder] to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 April 21 (Box-folder 001:114)
- Vida D. Scudder to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 April 26 (Box-folder 001:115)
- Josef L. Hromadka to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 May 3 (Box-folder 001:116)
- Norman Nash to Guy E. Shipler, 1954 May 7 (Box-folder 001:117)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 May 18 (Box-folder 001:118)
- Kit to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 June 8 (Box-folder 002:001)
- Lee [Rourde] to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 June 10 (Box-folder 002:002)
- Clifford K. Shipton to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 June 15 (Box-folder 002:003)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 June 17 (Box-folder 002:004)
- Thomas N. Carruthers to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 June 22 (Box-folder 002:005)
- Henry E. Horn to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 June 22 (Box-folder 002:006)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 June 24 (Box-folder 002:007)
- Amos N. Wilder to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 June 28 (Box-folder 002:008)
- [George R. Seleroy] to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 July 7 (Box-folder 002:009)
- Joseph M. Harte to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 July 9 (Box-folder 002:010)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 July 26 (Box-folder 002:011)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 July 29 (Box-folder 002:012)
- Marion Tait to Joseph and Forrest Fletcher, 1954 July 30 (Box-folder 002:013)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 August 7 (Box-folder 002:014)
- James A. Rockwell to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 August 11 (Box-folder 002:015)
- Russell L. Dicks to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 August 12 (Box-folder 002:016)
- E. F. M[ ] to Joseph and Forrest Fletcher, 1954 August 14 (Box-folder 002:017)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 August 19 (Box-folder 002:018)
- Nadia L. Hromadka to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 August 24 (Box-folder 002:019)
- Willard Uphaus to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 August 24 (Box-folder 002:020)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 September 7 (Box-folder 002:021)
- [Mrs. E. R.] Hatfield to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 September 24 (Box-folder 002:022)
- A. L. Byron-Curtiss to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 September 25 (Box-folder 002:023)
- [Guy Emery Shipler] to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure, 1954 October 6 (Box-folder 002:024)
- Wayne E. Oates to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 October 14 (Box-folder 002:025)
- J. Cyril Flanagan to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 October 19 (Box-folder 002:026)
- [Guy emery Shipler] to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 October 19 (Box-folder 002:027)
- Florence Converse to Forrest and Joseph Fletcher, 1954 October 22 (Box-folder 002:028)
- Otis R. Rice to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 October 22 (Box-folder 002:029)
- Alfred Zimmern to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 November 4 (Box-folder 002:030)
- Reagor Motlow to Joseph Fletcher, with enclosure, 1954 November 8 (Box-folder 002:031)
- Frederic B. Kellogg to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 November 9 (Box-folder 002:032)
- R. T. Boynton to Adjusters and Appraisers Limited [cc to Joseph Fletcher], 1954 November 12 (Box-folder 002:033)
- John Nevin Sayre to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 November 16 (Box-folder 002:034)
- Ted Ludlow to Joseph Fletcher, 1954 November 22 (Box-folder 002:035)